makitatools.com 2018-10-20

# MAKITA - Cordless and Corded Power Tools, Power Equipment, Pneumatics, Accessories

## Makita U.S.A., Inc. Privacy Policy

Thank you for your interest in our products and for visiting the makitatools.com web site. Makita U.S.A., Inc. (referred to in this policy as “we” or “us” or “our”) has created this privacy policy in order to demonstrate our firm commitment to your privacy. The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices on our website. By merely visiting makitatools.com you are not obligated to provide us with any personally-identifiable information. 

**Collection and Use of Non-Identifiable Information**  
We use one or more companies to place advertisements for our products and services and those of third parties on our Site and third-party sites. Cookies and other technologies such as Web beacons or tags are used to measure the effectiveness of our ads and to determine the display of content and advertising to you based on your interests both on our site, as well as on third-party sites where you may visit. To support this interest based advertising solution, we, and companies who we have contracted with, may use anonymous information about your visits to our and other Web sites. The information collected and used by this process is always anonymous, and does not enable any third-party to identify you individually.

Although it is our hope that you find the display of advertising to you based on your anonymous interests valuable, if you would prefer not to participate in the services offered through these solutions, you can always opt-out of this activity by visiting the Network Advertising Initiative (NAI) website by clicking <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>. 

**Collection and Use of Personally-Identifiable Information**  
We collect personally identifiable information from users of our website in a number of ways. 

__Registration__  
Our website's registration function allows you to voluntarily give us contact information such as your name, mailing address, email address and phone number. We use this information to ensure that you are eligible to register for members-only sections of our website, to send you information about our company and products, for marketing research, and to better serve you. 

__Order Forms__  
Our website incorporates order forms and similar functions by which you may request information, purchase products, complete product warranty registration and otherwise register for or request services. If you chose to complete these order forms or use these functions, you may be required to provide contact information, billing information and shipping information, as applicable. We use the information you provide to respond to your request, fulfill your order or provide the requested service, as applicable, and may use this information to send you information about our company and products. 

__Promotions/Online Surveys__  
We may run promotions or conduct online surveys on our website in which we ask you for contact information. We use this information in order to complete and fulfill the promotion, collect the survey or for the other purposes identified at the time of collection and may use this information to send you information about our company and products. 

**Marketing Communications and Targeting Advertisements**  
When we collect information from you as described above, we may include you in mailing lists for communications from us and our partners advertising products and services. We may also use your information to allow us to market more effectively through other websites and internet platforms, such as social media, including by placing targeted ads for our products and services. Our site provides you the opportunity to opt-out, on a prospective basis, of receiving marketing communications and targeted advertising through third party websites and platforms. This functionality is available at <https://www.makitatools.com/company/opt-out/>. Even if you opt out from receiving marketing communications and targeted advertising on other websites and platforms, you may still receive transactional emails from us such as warranty or product registration confirmations. You may also still see non-targeted advertisements that may be placed on other websites and platforms, including on social media where you are a member. 

In addition, we may send communications advertising our products and services to people who have not requested it. For example, a user of our website may request that we send our catalog or an e-mail newsletter to a friend. Each such mailing or e-mail (other than one-time mailings) will include simple instructions should you decide do not wish to receive mailings or e-mail from us. If at any time you request to be removed from our mailing list, no further mailings or e-mails will be sent to you once your request for removal has been processed. 

**Protection and Use of Personally-Identifiable Information**  
If you share personally-identifiable information with us, that information will be treated with strict confidentiality and only used or disclosed as provided in this policy or as you otherwise agree. Some of the products and services we offer, and some of our marketing activities, require us to share your personally-identifiable information with service providers we use to market or provide our products and services to you (for example, if you order replacement parts through our website, we will be required to provide your name and address to a shipping company to ship the parts to you). In order to market and provide these products and services to you, we must share certain personal information about you with these providers. We may also disclose your personal information to third parties that indirectly allow us to market and provide products and services to you. For example, our web hosting provider may have access to personal information transmitted through our website. In addition, we may disclose personal information pursuant to a subpoena or other legal requirement or to enforce our legal rights. 

Any personal information we collect will be stored in a secure location and will only be accessible by designated staff or authorized agents. We will require that any service providers with access to your personal information agree to maintain the confidentiality of this personal information in accordance with this policy. 

We will not sell, rent, or trade your specific personal information to a third party without your consent. However, we reserve the right to transfer data (including personally identifiable information collected through our website) to a buyer in connection with a sale of stock or assets, merger or any other similar transaction involving Makita USA Inc. if the buyer agrees to honor the promises of privacy that we have made to you. 

Occasionally, we may send summary data pertaining to our customers to third parties in order to enhance our products and services, but the summary information does not include any information that can personally be traced to you. 

**Links**  
Makitatools.com contains links to other sites. If you choose to leave this site via links to other non-Makita sites, including those of advertisers, we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. In addition, we are not responsible for the cookies those sites use. 

**Children**  
Our website is intended for use only by people 18 years of age or older. If you are not 18 years of age or older, please do not submit any personally identifiable information about yourself through our website or otherwise. We never knowingly target or collect personally identifiable information directly from children. We will not use any games, prizes or other activities/inducements directed at children for any purpose. 

**Internet Protocol (IP) Address and Technical Information Collection**  
An IP address is a number that is automatically assigned to your computer every time you browse the Internet. When users request a page from our site, our servers log the user's current IP address, certain information about your computer (such as your operating system, web browser information and screen resolution). Our servers may also track the number of visits to our site, how many times each page is accessed, the paths visitors take to access various pages and other usage details. This information is used to help us administer and improve our website, to identify unique visitors and to gather broad demographic information and compile general statistics. We may share this information in aggregated form (i.e., in a form that does not identify you specifically) with third parties and/or other affiliate marketing websites and/or web servers. We may also use third parties tracking technology to collect statistical information. 

**Cookies**  
Our website uses "cookie" technology. "Cookies" are strings of text that a website stores on a user's computer. Cookies enable us to keep track of our users' preferences and activities relating to our website. One way we use cookies is to save your password so you don't have to re-enter it each time you visit our site. If you choose not to receive these cookies, you may reset your browser to reject them (consult your particular browser instructions on how to do this.). Please note, however, that if you reject a cookie, certain areas of some sites may not function properly. 

**General**  
This Privacy Policy is effective as of November 5, 2009. This Privacy Policy may be updated at any time without prior notice by the posting of a modified version on our website so you should review this policy periodically. 

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, please send an email to [privacy@makitausa.com](mailto:privacy@makitausa.com). 

Updated: 6/27/2017
